Register to The Schneeloch Family Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Schneeloch Family Papers
1886-1910
MSS 6
Yale University Music Library
1.5
(3 boxes)
Diaries, correspondence, other materials by and about the American singers Emma Waleska Schneeloch Bacon (1862-1925) and Emilie Auguste Schneeloch Busse (b. 1868)
Schneeloch family
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Arrangement
In 5 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Printed matter. III. Miscellaneous. IV. Photographs. V. Addendum.
Scope and Contents
The Schneeloch Family Papers document the careers of Emma Schneeloch Bacon and Emilie Schneeloch Busse. The Papers include diaries, letters, programs, photographs, and newspaper clippings.
Additional information about the Schneeloch Family can be found in the Bacon-Schneeloch Family Papers, located in the Manuscripts and Archives Division of Yale University's Sterling Memorial Library.
Biographical / Historical
Emma Waleska Schneeloch Bacon (1862-1925) and Emilie Auguste Schneeloch Busse (b. 1868) were sisters from New Haven, Connecticut who became popular singers. Emma was a contralto, and Emilie a soprano. They frequently sang duets, but they were best known as members of a vocal quartet associated with Patrick Gilmore's band. The Schneeloch sisters made two national concert tours with Gilmore's band.
Music -- United States -- 19th century; Singers -- Correspondence; Singers -- Diaries; Bacon, Emma Waleska Schneeloch, 1862-1925; Busse, Emilie Auguste Schneeloch; Clodio, Victor; Gilmore, P. S. (Patrick Sarsfield), 1829-1892; Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962; Whitney, Myron William, 1836-1910; Schneeloch family
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Diary, Emilie Schneeloch's of Western Trip with Gilmore's band, Oct 15, 1891-Dec 20, 1891; 55 typed pages (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diary, Emilie Schneeloch's of Western Trip with Gilmore's band, Apr 17, 1892-May 28, 1892; 27 typed pages (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Browning, (?), no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Burdett, O., 1886 Jun 26; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gilmore P.S., 1886 Mar 7; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spenser, Williard, 1886 Jun 3; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vade, Walter, 1886 Aug 30; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Valencia Boat Club, 1886 Jan 23; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Burling, Clinton, 1888 Nov 12; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Foerster, Wilhelm, 1890 Feb 6; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Trowbridge, J.J., no date; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Schneeloch, Emilie, no date; poem (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Schneeloch, Emil, 1907 Jan 3; autograph letter signed (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 5 telegrams (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - no date, 13 unidentified items (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 21 life insurence receipts (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 16 callcards (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Printed Matter, Series II
  - Printed Matter, printed matter (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1876, printed programme (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1885, 6 printed programmes (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1886, 16 printed programmes (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1886, 28 printed programmes (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1887, 26 printed programmes (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1888, 15 printed programmes (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1889, 9 printed programmes (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1889, 9 printed programmes (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1890, 8 printed programmes (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1891, 17 printed programmes (duplicata) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1891, 6 printed programmes (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1892, 2 printed programmes (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1893, 3 printed programmes (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - no date, programmes (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - no date, 15 printed programmes (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous, Series III
  - Programmes, 1888-1891 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1888-1891 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous and clippings (Box 2, Folder 9)
    General
    Newspaper clipping, Sep 5, 1965 New York Times, Sunday, about Patrick Sarsfield Gilmore
- Photographs, Series IV
  - Kreisler, Fritz, no date; autographed photograph (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Schneeloch sisters and friends, no date; photograph (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Frank Busse and his wife, Millie Schneeloch Busse, no date; photograph (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Gilmore's Great Quartette: P.S. Gilmore, Emma and Emilie Schneeloch, Myron W. Whitney, Signor Victor Clodio, no date; photograph (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - unidentified, no date; 5 photographs (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Addendum, 1880-1901; Series V
  - 1 scrapbook, newspaper clippings, 1880-1892 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1 file, newspaper clippings, 1889-1892 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1 pamphlet and notes on performing techniques, no date (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1 publicity brochure, no date (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - miscellaneous programs, 1887-1901 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1 music notebook, no date (Box 3, Folder 6)